### SASHA MILLER

Lodi CA | (209) 224-7518 | sashazm85@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front-End web developer with a focus on using semantic markup, scalable CSS and JavaScript to build highly performant, responsive, and accessible websites. Specializing in turning design concepts into working themes in Drupal. Involvement in local code meetups and developer conferences since 2013 has built a foundation of community collaboration resulting in constant improvements to both hard and soft skills.

#### **SKILLS**

**Trilingual:** English, Russian, and Ukrainian

**Software:** Visual Studio Code, Windows (WSL2), Bash, Adobe Photoshop/XD **Languages:** JavaScript (ES5/6+), CSS/SASS, HTML, Twig, PHP (enough for theming)

Frameworks/CMS: Drupal 8+, Vue, WordPress, Gatsby.js, React

Other: OOP, Git, Node.js/NPM, CSS Grid, Jira, Acquia, Site Improve, Lando, Agile

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **University of California San Francisco Contract Developer** 2019 – Present Flagship UCSF.edu Website

- Raised the site's total "Site Improve" accessibility score from 63/100 to 95/100 furthering one of the University's core values of Diversity by allowing visitors with disabilities to more effortlessly use the site
- Refactored the main menu for accessibility via keyboard tabbing and ARIA attributes which ensured the entire site could be easily navigable
- Upgraded outdated code to run more efficiently by lazy loading images, reducing layout shift, splitting files for quicker simultaneous downloads by browsers, and isolating code to either run in only desktop or mobile
- Integrated Google Maps API for displaying campus locations
- Programmed multiple improvements with JavaScript to allow content editors to better craft and lay out visually compelling pages through tools such as custom CKEditor Widgets
- Constructed a number of new User Interface enhancements such as sticky nav, social share card customization, and third-party Virtual Tour integrations enriching the experience expected from a flagship site

#### **Magazine Site**

- Utilized JavaScript skills to create multiple interactive elements such as Carousels and Mega-menus which complimented and brought to life the stunning aesthetic of the design
- Advised team on animation best practices concerning menu accessibility and iterated through multiple prototypes to allow the stakeholder to opt for a solution that satisfied criteria for both usability and panache

#### **Giving Site**

- Within limited budget, renovated the site to attract new donors
- Reskinned the site based on update mockups by using CSS

#### **BARC RNA Conference and Registration**

- Drupal site building of event scheduling system for conference website
- Automated visibility of session content based upon scheduled dates, audience type, and content ownership criteria resulting in a secure and structured release of information to attendees at appropriate times
- Implemented an internal Five-star system for organizers to rate sessions
- Networked with Drupal community to reuse existing practices and event system code to ensure completing the site by conference kickoff

#### IT/HR Vue.js Theming and Permissions

- Duplicated the existing Vue-only theme into a traditional Drupal Twig theme per the requirement for it to optionally be used without the dependence on Vue.js
- Abstracted redundant code into reusable Vue "components" and "mixins" which reduced the surface area for potential bugs
- Adopted the IT site's access controls into the HR site ensuring better security while simultaneously supplying a friendlier user experience by utilizing a consistent interface across both sites

#### **Collaboration with Internal UCSF Team**

- Perform risk assessments concerning the feasibility of implementing new features, estimating complexity and the duration to complete tasks
- Navigate client expectations to work within hard deadlines
- Thoroughly document code both inline and within tickets to provide others clarity into how code functions and its desired outcome
- Able to self-motivate and follow through the completion of tasks before deadlines with minimal supervision
- Encourage team coding practices of Git and Gitflow branching strategies

#### Freelance Web Developer 2019 - Present

- Implement Responsive Web Design best practices to create performant websites usable on all devices and screen sizes
- Craft scalable (S)CSS architecture with BEM (Block, Element, Modifier) allowing easy maintenance through component scoping
- Utilize Gatsby.js to create JAMstack websites using React
- Build & maintain custom sites and themes in Drupal 8 and Wordpress
- Make custom Wordpress Gutenberg blocks in React to allow ease of content editing
- Automate end-to-end testing with Cypress and continuous integration using CircleCl

#### **Private Nanny and Homemaker** 2002 - 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Crimean Regional Bible College** Simferopol, Ukraine

- Graduated 2003 with a degree in Children's Ministry
- 4.92 GPA (5 point grading scale)